Hameet S. Boparai

Full Stack Developer

(NZ Citizen, Wellington)

Portfolio Site
AWS Certification
02102471762

<u>hameet.singh@hotmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/hameet-boparai</u> <u>https://github.com/Hameet</u>

A Full stack developer, technical writer and confident public speaker, seeking a new challenging career in the technology sector after several years of being a microbiology technician.

I am a graduate from Enspiral Dev Academy's intense 18-week Full Stack Developer boot camp who is looking for a junior developer role to develop my current skill set further.

Technical Skills & Stack

Technologies and tools:

- o Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, some Python3
- o SQLite3, Express.js server
- o React, Redux, Redux-Observable
- o RESTful APIs, Styled Components
- o Git, Github and NPM
- o Test Driven Development with Jest, Enzyme and Test Cafe
- o AWS Cloud Computing (EC2, VPC etc.)

Recent Projects:

Wellington JavaScript for juniors - Code

A project sponsored in part by BNZ and overseen by highly experienced developers who are leading a group of Junior Devs including me to create a state-of-the-art JavaScript application for a local charity. More info here

Embracing Blue - Code

This was my final project at EDA. A full stack app created to deal with mental health issues. It was built using React, Redux, Express, Auth etc. I had a great time working with my team and learned about agile development and how to connect the back end to the Front end.

Hacker-News-Api - Code

A personal project consisting of a front end web news app connected to the hacker news website via a RESTful Api. I used a mixture of functional and OOP methods. The components have been tested with the Jest framework.

Mush-to-Muscles - Code

An on-going personal project of mine I am using as an online diary to make and store workout plans. This is a full stack app using technologies similar to the projects above.

Transferable Skills

Agile Developer: Implement agile management ideals by facilitating exercises such as sprint planning and team standups. Ensure high quality code by using pair programming approach. I've worked in teams which have used both Kanban and SCRUM iterative methods.

Willingness to learn: I'm continuously learning new things about coding languages and improving the quality and quantity of my code.

Communication: All of my previous roles have required excellent communication with colleagues, internal stakeholders and management. I have also presented to large audiences at work. I've excellent listening, empathy and feedback skills which I've used in both professional and academic environments.

Work ethic: Throughout my career, my high level of integrity and care for my work has led to employers developing a high level of trust and increased responsibilities.

Leadership: I have trained and supervised new staff numerous times and have filled in for a superior from time to time.

Project Management: Working as a Quality Control Technician for MSD I was in charge of several projects. I routinely worked with different internal stakeholders to change or improve existing testing/production processes or to create new methods and procedures from scratch. This also involved correspondence with international stakeholders in the US and the EU.

Technical Writing: Working in Quality Control I've written extensive investigation reports, project proposals, SOPs and validation documents.

Employment History

Enspiral Dev Academy (Wellington)

Jan 2018 – May 2018

Full Stack Developer (Student/Apprentice)

At EDA I didn't only learn new technologies but subsequently used them to create websites. Some of the technical and human skills I've acquired are:

- > JavaScript frameworks such as React, Redux, Jest etc. and the importance of testing your code.
- ➤ How to write the business logic required in order to manipulate data to achieve what you want in your web app. The basics of CRUD.
- > A vast array of human skills through working in a diverse environment and pair programming
- A better understanding of communication techniques for conflict resolution and team work
- At EDA Presentation skills were also greatly emphasized and I've acquired a new-found confidence in my verbal communication
- Ye come to realize my passion for Front end development, UI, UX and the logic of back end

Merck Sharpe & Dohme - Wellington

August 2014 – Mar 2018

Position Held: Quality Control Laboratory Technician

I have worked as a QC laboratory technician in the QC Sterility department for MSD-AH. A large part of my job was Technical Writing (reports, investigations & SOP's etc.). Some of my duties included:

- Control testing on veterinary vaccines, intermediate components, solutions, raw materials, complaint samples and development samples to meet regulatory requirements
- ➤ Writing Method and Process validations to implement new or improve current testing procedures
- Accurately record all test data and observations in accordance with Good Documentation Practices
- ➤ Collaborated with Internal Stakeholders on projects to improve and validate new protocols for both testing and production
- Performed Document control and accurately maintained databases and records

Asure Quality (Auckland)

May 2011- Aug 2014

Position Held: Laboratory Technician

I have worked in different divisions of the Microbiology department of Asure Quality.

- > Operated laboratory equipment such as PCR (DNA replication) among others
- Assisted in setting up various projects and setting up all the necessary paperwork
- Answered customer queries regarding results or delays in testing
- > Investigated situations wherein the inter-laboratory mistakes need to be tackled

Education

- ➤ **2018:** Full Stack Developer Boot Camp *Enspiral Dev Academy*
- **2009-2010:** Graduate Diploma in Laboratory Technology majoring in Microbiology, chemistry and Food Technology from *Christchurch Polytechnic Institute of Technology*
- ➤ 2005-2008: Bachelor of Science (Biotechnology) from Guru Nanak Dev University (India)

Personal Interests

I have an eclectic taste in especially Music and Film but I also enjoy reading and video games.

References

Theresa Thomas (Quality Control Manager, MSD) **Charles F Munat** (Technical Coach, BNZ) Mobile: 027-886-0425

Mobile: 021-226-8628